Jose Molina

israel.molina@gmail.com • 407-965-7030 • Sanford, FL

www.josemolinaresume.com • https://github.com/jimolina • https://www.linkedin.com/in/joseisraelmolina

Permanent Work Authorization • No Visa Sponsorship Required • Open to Relocation

Professional Summary

Web Developer with more than 20+ years of experience designing, architecting, integrating and supporting corporate web tools and applications; skilled in development across intranets, front-end, back-end, content management, e-commerce and database architecture

Technical Skills

Front-end	Back-end	Vendors Implementation	Extras
 Html 5 Less / Sass Css 3 Bootstrap JavaScript Ajax / Json JQuery / Dojo / Kendo ReactJs / AngularJs Razor DNN 	 Php Zend Laravel Codelgniter CakePhp MySql MsSql DB2 MongoDB 	 BrightCove STN Bitmovin Google Analytics Adobe Analytics Adobe Primetime Pubmatic Sprinserver Taboola OpenWeb Google Ad Manager SportRadar 	 Git / SourceTree / BitBucket Jira / Confluence / Crucible Spring Loops Gulp Browsersync Balsamic Wordpress / WP VIP / CLI Magento Photoshop / Figma / LightRoom Windows Office Suite

Bilingual

Spanish and English

Professional Experience

NESN.com
Senior Web Developer (2020 - 2022) > Senior Full Stack Engineer (2022 - Present)

06/2020 - Present Watertown, MS - Usa

- Developing NESN.com using: WP VIP, Vanila JS, ReactJS, PHP, CSS3, SASS, Json.
- Creation of Endpoints to deliver data to Mobile Apps.
- Maintenance of the Subscription system (ReactJs + Stripe)
- Custom implementation of the Roku OTT activation flow
- Integrating Video Players vendors like: BrightCove, STN, and Bitmovin.
- Integrating Data Analytics vendors like: Google Analytics, Adobe Analytics.
- Integrating MVPD vendor like: Adobe Primetime.
- Integrating Ads vendors like: Pubmatic, Sprinserver, Taboola, OpenWeb, and Google Ad Manager.
- Integrating Sport Data vendor like: SportRadar.
- Attend daily StandUp meetings, 2 weeks Sprints, and planning sprint in base of story points.
- Use GitHub to manage each Jira ticket as a new feature/fix/hotfix branch.
- Created code snipers documentation in Confluence and share with the others developers in the team.

Smashfly.com Front End Developer

08/2017 - 04/2020 Concord, MS - Usa

- Developed the Career Sites for customer like: CVS, Columbia, Canon, Zillow, Groupon.
- Developed using: Razor .NET environment and DNN platform.
- Use Json objects to manage all the data in the front-end, like data grids.
- Extensive use of Jquery and Kendo to provide the user experience required for each customer.
- Use of Gulp to automate the creation of .css files for Dev / QA / Production (.min version) environments.
- Normalization of css class using Bootstrap 4.
- Implemented SASS node component with Visual Studio Code.
- Attend daily StandUp meetings, 2 weeks Sprints, and planning sprint in base of story points.
- Use GitHub to manage each Jira ticket as a new feature/fix/hotfix branch.
- Created code snipers documentation in Confluence and share with the others developers in the team.

- Developed an online application providing a full system solution for the Public School Systems.
- Designed application to replace a thirty-year-old COBOL program.
- Developed using: Php Zend Framework and DB2.
- Executed Ajax calls to the Db2 and Cobol programs to obtain Json Objects.
- Use Json objects to manage all the data in the front-end, like data grids.
- Use of Rest url to manage the data grid and CRUD pages.
- Extensive use of Dojo and Jquery to provide the same behaviors the previous COBOL program provided.
- Use of Gulp to automate the creation of .css files for Dev / QA / Production (.min version) environments.
- Normalization of css class using Bootstrap 3.
- Attend daily SCRUM meetings, 2 weeks sprint and planning sprint in base of Story Points.
- Use of Jira for ticket management. Confluence for create documentation.
- Use of Balsamic to create mockups.
- Created sprite image with Photoshop.
- Use git/sourcetree to manage each ticket as a new feature branch.
- Use Spring Loops for continue sandbox deploy.
- Implemented Less node component with Zend framework. Created the documentation for this task and share with the others developers in the team.

Your Gentle Dentist Inc. Web Developer

01/2013 - 01/2014 Lake Mary, Florida - USA

- Implementation of WP theme.
- Implementation of meeting/appointment schedule api.
- Use of Php, Css and JQuery to customize theme and maintain data.
- Server (emails, data, Google analytics) maintains.

Adverweb Junior Developer / Senior Developer / Support Manager

06/2004 – 03/2012 Caracas - Venezuela

IT Consulting firm specializing in corporate websites, e-commerce and content management, with +30 staff and providing services in 4 countries: Venezuela, USA, Panama, and Italy

Support Manager

06/2008 – 03/2012

- Managed team of 4 including designers, developers and social media manager; provided 360° reviews and supervised technical test hiring; reported monthly status to General Manager.
- Created technical scope in base of brainstorming, white boarding and scrum meetings.
- Use of MS Project for delivered final schedule and activities to my team.
- Use MS Visio for database documentation.
- Use SugarCRM for keep tracking of tickets assigned.
- Optimized newspaper website time load by 72%, using better practices in MySQL and JQuery functions.
- Provided technical support for software changes and new requirements to projects in production.
- Managed customer deliverables by controlling and scheduling times and activities of project phases.
- Reduced website bugs by 94% in all projects before final customer review, used test documentation by module and functionality.

Senior Developer

06/2006 – 06/2008

- Scheduled activities of project's phases between team members.
- Implemented Code Reviews to check each module in all projects.
- Developed ecommerce using Php, Mysql, Html5, Css3.
- Integrated paypal as pay platform for ecommerce website.
- Created an educational website to manage all the student/parents information. Also payroll and daily student schedule, using Php, MySql, Html, Css2, JavaScript, Ajax.
- Responsible for the view layout, pagination, and final integration of Php code for a newspaper website.

Junior Developer

06/2004 - 06/2006

- Use Php and MySql for create corporative website.
- Created a Rest CRUD website application for Real Estate company using Php, MySql, Css2, JavaScript.
- Maintain version control on all development projects through SVN.
- Implement a security code to prevent sql injections over all the website created in the company.

EDUCATION

Electrical Engineering 1998 Universidad Bicentenaria

Universidad Bicentenaria Venezuela

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT/AFFILIATIONS

Accessibility for Web Design	LinkedIn Learning	2023
Git Essential Training	LinkedIn Learning	2023
Learning Django	LinkedIn Learning	2023
Learning ReactJs	LinkedIn Learning	2020
Learning Vagrant	LinkedIn Learning	2020
PHP 7 New Features	LinkedIn Learning	2020
Test-Driven Development in Django	LinkedIn Learning	2020
WordPress: Developing Blocks with Gutenberg	LinkedIn Learning	2020
CTRM	SmashFly Transform Academy	2018/Certification
English as a Second Language (ESOL)	Seminole State College of Florida, Usa	2012/Course
Digital Photography	Roberto Mata, Venezuela	2012/Course
Digital Photography & Lighting Studio	Escuela Foto Arte, Venezuela	2012/Course
Ethical Hacking	Condo Consulting, Venezuela	2009/Course
PHP Developer	PHP de Venezuela, Venezuela	2009/Certification